# Adrien Lacquemant

alaq.io - github.com/alaq - linkedin.com/in/adrien-lacquemant/

adrien@alaq.io +1 (646) 410-3409

### SUMMARY

Two years of experience as a JavaScript developer delivering creative highly data-driven client-centric applications. I am excited to be part of a team and solve problems using my experience in spotting inefficiencies and creating automated solutions.

### SKILLS

- Proficient: JavaScript, React/Redux, React-Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, HTML/CSS
- Knowledgeable: Git, TypeScript, Agile, Firebase, Serverless, SQL, unit testing with Mocha/Chai/Enzyme, IATEX

#### EXPERIENCE

## Fullstack Academy of Code - major coding bootcamp

New York, NY

Dec 2017 - Apr 2018

- Teaching Fellow
  - $\circ~$  Led code reviews and acted as a project manager for 4 teams of junior software engineers.
  - Taught algorithms, whiteboarding problems, back-end and front-end development in JavaScript.
    Code paired, debugged/mentored technical concepts and best practices to 50 students on a daily basis.
  - Led technical interviews in Javascript for prospective students 2 to 3 times a week.
- **Ara Global Group** medium sized electronics wholesaler CTO

New York, NY

May 2016 - Apr 2018

- Spearheaded re-engineering project to improve/automate asset processing and cataloging, reducing processing time by 25%.
- o Developed an in-house SaaS for systematic asset and sales monitoring per device leading to 20% in increased revenue.
- Wrote a data validation tool in JavaScript that ensured the accuracy of inventory and sales data feeds.
- o Launched new Miami branch, recruiting, training and managing a team of 20 employees within 8 weeks.

## **BISAM**, **Inc.** – financial software vendor

New York, NY

Product Support Analyst

Jan 2015 - Apr 2016

- o Troubleshot financial calculation issues raised by clients and Professional Services team.
- Solved complex business and technical issues, using financial formulas.
- Supported defect resolution by identifying and replicating bugs.
- $\circ\,$  Testing patch releases and managing deliveries.

## Tortus Capital Management - value oriented hedge fund

New York, NY

Research Analyst

Jul 2013 - Jul 2014

- Completed financial analysis for over 30 distressed companies and recommended long/short positions.
- o Traded and monitored the firm's securities on a daily basis.

#### PROJECTS

# Propel ML – open source contributor

https://github.com/propelml/propel

 $GPU\mbox{-}backed\ numpy\mbox{-}like\ infrastructure\ for\ scientific\ computing\ in\ JavaScript.$ 

Feb 2018 to Present

- Contributing to the front-end of a large Preact/Typescript open source project, using TDD.
- $\circ\,$  Implementing of user profiles, and several other front-end features.

# summaries.io – developer

https://github.com/npm-install/summaries.io

 $A\ personal\ daily\ news\ summary,\ in\ text\ and\ audio\ podcast$ 

Dec 2017

- $\circ\,$  Progressive web application built by a Test-First Agile team with Javascript using Node.js and React.
- o Fully serverless deployments of Node.js microservices using Google Cloud Functions and Firestore.

## Device Extract, LLC. - founder & developer

 $An\ Electron\ app\ for\ cataloging\ mobile\ devices\ programmatically$ 

June 2017 - Present

- o Built with Electron, to access Android and iOS devices through the computer's serial ports.
- $\circ$  Scanned over 100,000 mobile devices successfully; extracting characteristics and basic diagnostics.

### **EDUCATION**

## Fullstack Academy of Code

New York, NY

 $Software\ Engineering\ Immersive\ Program$ 

2017

M.S. Financial Techniques

2013

Universite Paris Dauphine

**ESSEC Business School** 

Paris, France 2011

M.S. Finance & B.S. Economics

Singapore

Adrien Lacquemant +1 (646) 410-3409 adrien@alaq.io